A Guide to the Bill of Rights Tour, 1990-1993
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Bill of Rights Tour, 1990-1993
The Library of Virginia
41491, 35415, 35546, 34930
3 c.f. (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years (Code of Virginia 42.1-78). Financial records: 2.2-3705.1(9); 2.2-3801(2) and personal information - social security numbers (2.2-3801).] It will be necessary for an archivist to review and remove or redact confidential records or information before the records can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies can be made. If you are planning to use these records, please contact Archives Reference Services for more details prior to planning your research trip.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by the Library of Virginia in several different accessions in 1995, 1997, and 2004.
Biographical Information
In 1990, Virginia's original, hand scribed copy of the Bill of Rights toured the United States as part of a traveling exhibit to celebrate its 200th anniversary. There are only 14 official copies of the Bill of Rights, one for the federal government and one for each of the original 13 colonies. The exhibit was sponsored by the Phillip Morris Company who collaborated with the Library of Virginia (then the Virginia State Library and Archives) who loaned the Bill of Rights. The tour started in Barre, VT on October 10, 1990 and concluded in Richmond, VA on December 11-15, 1991. The "Grand Finale" included a parade and a ball held at the Jefferson Hotel.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of multiple accessions from the Library of Virginia Office of the State Librarian and Office of the State Archivist relating to the Bill of Rights Tour including: 41491, 35415, 35546, and 34930.
Accession 41491 documents the planning and execution of the tour, as well as the "Grand Finale" of the tour and potential exhibits after the tours conclusion. The records include agreements and memorandums of understanding, insurance policies, conservation evaluations and materials, travel reimbursements and documentation, timetables, promotional materials, memos, correspondence, photographs, and other related materials.
Accession 35415 documents the Bill of Rights tour including the planning of the grand finale reception in Richmond, VA in December 1991. It contains correspondence, notes, newsletters, clippings, pamphlets, photographs, and press releases.
Accession 35546 documents the logistics each stop on the tour. The records include exhibit files, floor plans, employee lists, security files, insurance contracts, leases, reimbursement checks, promotional materials, as well as correspondence and other related materials. It also includes architectural drawings for the exhibition set up, as well as posters for the exhibit.
Accession 34930 documents the planning of the tour as well as potential exhibits after its conclusion. The records include correspondence and notes, tour update newsletters, photographs, newspaper clippings, plans for a Boy Scout patch, as well as a video of the first stop on the tour and the Philadelphia Bicentennial exhibition.
Arrangement
The collections are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Bill of Rights Tour Files (41491), 1990-1993., Extent: 1 box.
  - Philip Morris Agreement and Planning Records, 1990. (Folder 1)
  - Conservation Records, 1990. (Folder 2-3)
  - Consulting Services, 1990-1992. (Folder 4)
  - Commission Records, 1990. (Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1990. (Folder 6)
  - Commission Records, 1991 Undated-Aug. (Folder 7)
  - Commission Records, 1991 Sept-Dec. (Folder 8)
  - Financial Records, 1991 Jan-June. (Folder 9)
  - Financial Records, 1991 July-Dec. (Folder 10)
  - Promotional Materials, 1991. (Folder 11)
  - Libraries are Worth It Rally, 1991. (Folder 12)
  - Grand Finale Timetable, 19901. (Folder 13)
  - Bicentennial Ball, 1991. (Folder 14)
  - Seville Exposition, 1991. (Folder 15)
  - Post Tour Exhibit, 1991-1993. (Folder 16)
  - Commission Records, 1992. (Folder 17)
  - Financial Records, 1992-1993. (Folder 18)
- Bill of Rights Exhibit Tour Files (35546), 1990-1991., Extent: 1 box, 1 architectural tube.
  - Raleigh, NC Jan 12-16. (Folder 1)
  - Montgomery, AL Jan 22-23. (Folder 2)
  - Tallahassee, FL Jan 27-30. (Folder 3)
  - Knoxville and Nashville, TN Feb 1-7. (Folder 4)
  - Baton Rouge, LA Feb 11-17. (Folder 5)
  - Little Rock, AR Feb 20-24. (Folder 6)
  - Dallas, TX Mar 2-5. (Folder 7)
  - Houston, TX Mar 8-12. (Folder 8)
  - Oklahoma City, OK March 14-17. (Folder 9)
  - Topeka, KS Mar 21-24. (Folder 10)
  - Lincoln, NE Mar 27-30. (Folder 11)
  - Albuquerque, NM Apr 4-7. (Folder 12)
  - Phoenix, AZ Apr 11-14. (Folder 13)
  - Las Vegas, NV Apr 18-21. (Folder 14)
  - Oakland and San Fransisco, CA Apr 25-29. (Folder 15)
  - Salt Lake City, UT May 2-4. (Folder 16)
  - Los Angeles, CA May 8-12. (Folder 17)
  - Honolulu, HI May 23-28. (Folder 18)
  - Portland, OR June 19-23. (Folder 19)
  - Juneau, AK July 2-7. (Folder 20)
  - Seattle, WA July 13-16. (Folder 21)
  - Boise, ID July 19-22. (Folder 22)
  - Billings, MT July 25-28. (Folder 23)
  - Bismark, ND Aug 1-4. (Folder 24)
  - Casper, WY Aug 14-19. (Folder 25)
  - Davenport, IA Aug 19-23. (Folder 26)
  - Denver, CO Aug 29-Sept 3. (Folder 27)
  - Sioux Falls, SD Sept 6-10. (Folder 28)
  - St. Paul, MN Sept 13-16. (Folder 29)
  - Kansas City, MO Sept 20-24. (Folder 30)
  - Indianapolis, IN Oct 3-6. (Folder 31)
  - Biloxi, MS Oct 12-15. (Folder 32)
  - Chicago, IL Oct 24-28. (Folder 33)
  - Louiseville, KY Oct 31-Nov 3. (Folder 34)
  - Milwaukee, WI Nov 7-10. (Folder 35)
  - Detroit, MI Nov 13-17. (Folder 36)
  - Cleveland, OH Nov 20-24. (Folder 37)
  - Charleston, WV Nov 27-Dec 1. (Folder 38)
  - Richmond, VA Dec 11-15. (Folder 39)
  - STV (Folder 40)
  - Stolow, Nathan (Folder 41)
  - Architectural Drawings (Box 1)
  - Tour Posters (Box 1)
- Bill of Rights Tour Files (35415), 1987, 1991., Extent: 1 box (.35 c.f.)
  - Constitutional Convention Bicentennial Materials, 1987. (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1991. (Folder 2-3)
  - Exhibit Photographs, 1991. (Folder 4)
  - LIFE Bill of Rights Publication, 1991. (Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1991. (Folder 6)
  - Publicity Clippings and Copies, 1991. (Folder 7)
- Bill of Rights Tour Files (34930), 1990-1993., Extent: 1 box (.35 c.f.)
  - First Amendment Congress, 1990. (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1990-1991. (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1990-1994. (Folder 3)
  - Tour Updates, 1990-1992. (Folder 4)
  - Photographs and publications, 1990-1992. (Folder 5)
  - Boy Scout Patch, 1991. (Folder 6)
  - Seville Expo, 1991. (Folder 7)
  - Post Tour Exhibit Materials, 1992-1993. (Folder 8)
  - VHS Tapes. (Folder 9)